<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-09T20:25:27-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Disorganized Behavior</title><subtitle>A blog about social, behavioral, and information sciences</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How artificial intelligence augments human intelligence</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/research/2021/12/06/augmented-intelligence.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How artificial intelligence augments human intelligence" /><published>2021-12-06T12:28:08-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-06T12:28:08-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/research/2021/12/06/augmented-intelligence</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research/2021/12/06/augmented-intelligence.html">&lt;p&gt;In the debate about how artificial intelligence (AI) affects employment and productivity, the two sides argue something like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eventually, machines will be able to do everything a human can do, and they’ll do it better, faster, and more cheaply.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Machines will never replace human workers, only enhance their productivity by serving as advanced tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you qualify each claim as optimistic or pessimistic depends on what you value, and let’s put values aside for the moment. Yet it remains a worthwhile question to ask, who’s right? Does the continued development and application of AI mean that machines will replace humans, or that humans will be able to do things they never could before?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davies &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;’s recent article in &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-04086-x&quot;&gt;“Advancing mathematics by guiding human intuition with AI”&lt;/a&gt; presents several cases in pure math where researchers used AI to solve important problems that the brightest mathemeticians had yet to solve on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With AI, mathemticians sort of have a sounding board for their intuitions—they can model the relationships between purely conceptual mathematical objects and see what kinds of patterns emerge. This role for AI places it somewhere above a tool; there are social and cognitive components of AI’s role in pure math research that make it more like a collaborator. But it’s still far less than an independent researcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I think this is an excellent role for AI: increasing productivity and supporting research by augmenting human capabilities. With research getting more difficult, funding getting scarcer, and global problems requiring a faster pace of innovation, I am excited to see how else AI can help researchers do their jobs better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">In the debate about how artificial intelligence (AI) affects employment and productivity, the two sides argue something like the following:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trust in science rises, still low overall</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/research/2021/12/06/trust-in-science.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trust in science rises, still low overall" /><published>2021-12-06T12:28:08-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-06T12:28:08-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/research/2021/12/06/trust-in-science</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research/2021/12/06/trust-in-science.html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/01/science/scientist-trust-poll.html&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; late last month on new data from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wellcome.org/reports/wellcome-global-monitor-covid-19/2020&quot;&gt;Wellcome/Gallup poll&lt;/a&gt;. The headline finding was that “trust in science and scientists increased globally” between 2018 and 2020. The report notes that trust in science is correlated with knowing about science and speculates that the change in public attitudes was due to media coverage during the pandemic that brought people closer to scientists and scientific research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That knowing about science correlates with trust in science doesn’t surprise me. Knowing, liking, and trusting are all closely related constructs. Further, the more you know, the less you have to trust: with total ignorance, trust is unwarranted, and with perfect knowledge, trust is unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did surprise me about the report and the article was how the authors all took it for granted how low trust in science is overall. Even in 2020, after trust had risen, less than half of respondents said they trusted science a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, scientists are only human and prone to the same kinds of mistakes and misbehavior as anyone else, but there are lots of reasons to trust science as a whole. Where is the gap between the rigor and expertise in scientific practice and trust in science by the public?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">The Times reported late last month on new data from a Wellcome/Gallup poll. The headline finding was that “trust in science and scientists increased globally” between 2018 and 2020. The report notes that trust in science is correlated with knowing about science and speculates that the change in public attitudes was due to media coverage during the pandemic that brought people closer to scientists and scientific research.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trust in science rises, still low overall</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/advice/2021/12/06/advice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trust in science rises, still low overall" /><published>2021-12-06T12:28:08-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-06T12:28:08-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/advice/2021/12/06/advice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/advice/2021/12/06/advice.html">&lt;p&gt;In this post, I will try out a sort of advice column. Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/unanswered/What-shall-I-do-if-I-am-feeling-so-exhausted-but-I-don-t-want-to-rest&quot;&gt;question from Quora&lt;/a&gt; that has not received any answers yet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-shall-i-do-if-i-am-feeling-so-exhausted-but-i-dont-want-to-rest&quot;&gt;What shall I do if I am feeling so exhausted but I don’t want to rest?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You say you are exhausted but don’t want to rest. In their most general meanings, ‘rest’ is the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; treatment for ‘exhaustion’. So perhaps you have particular ideas about one or the other that appears incompatible with the states of ‘exhaustion’ and ‘rest’ that you are experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, if ‘rest’ means ‘sleep’ to you, you can certainly be exhausted but not desire sleep. Conversely, if ‘exhausted’ means ‘sleepy’, and you are not ready to go to sleep yet, most other forms of rest may be unappealing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without knowing what you mean by these terms, it is difficult to say what you should do. But I encourage you to broaden your ideas of what it means to be ‘exhausted’ and what it means to ‘rest’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can better understand the nature and cause of your exhaustion, you might find a more descriptive label for it that leads to a solution. Are you sleepy, tired, or wiped? Burnt out, depressed, or drained? Bored, lethargic, or stuck? What will make you feel better depends on what you are feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you better understand how you’re feeling, consider forms of rest that might not be obvious. Even if you are not ready for sleep or feel too agitated or bored to lie down, there are lots of activities that can be restful: enjoying a show, movie, book, or game; engaging with a hobby or puzzle; hanging out with family and friends; or exercising or playing a sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to specify what you mean by ‘exhausted’ and then offer yourself the kind of rest that mathes it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="advice" /><summary type="html">In this post, I will try out a sort of advice column. Here’s a question from Quora that has not received any answers yet:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An absence of evidence of community policing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/research/2021/12/01/absence-of-evidence.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An absence of evidence of community policing" /><published>2021-12-01T13:44:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-01T13:44:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/research/2021/12/01/absence-of-evidence</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research/2021/12/01/absence-of-evidence.html">&lt;p&gt;The lead research article of the most recent issue of &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.abd3446&quot;&gt;“Community policing does not build citizen trust in police or reduce crime in the Global South”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research was a collaboration of 27 researchers in five countries to run a large-scale field experiment across South America, Africa, and Asia. When these studies are published, it’s a big deal, if for no other reason than the difficulty and cost of executing a study of this scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because high-quality empirical research is necessarily so scarce, these large-scale field experiments carry a lot of weight with policy wonks, and, one hopes, policymakers. When arguing for or against a community policing program, someone, somewhere, is going to cite this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On its face, that’s not really a problem. But they’re going to cite the article without actually reading it. It’s almost inevitable. Scientific articles are long, dense, highly technical, and, frankly, a bit repetitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why it’s so important to get the headline right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And why I’m frustrated that this one is misleading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not wrong, &lt;em&gt;per se&lt;/em&gt;. But “Community policing does not build citizen trust in police or reduce crime in the Global South” implies a certain pair of relationships that the study doesn’t even really analyze:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enacting community policing behaviors does not lead to higher levels of citizen trust in police.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enacting community policing behaviors does not reduce crime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these propositions, I have made explicit what the title implies the independent variable in the study is. But community policing itself is not the actual independent variable in the study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, the study looked at police reforms &lt;em&gt;intended&lt;/em&gt; to lead to community policing and found that they did not succeed in doing so: “The police implemented the interventions unevenly and incompletely…[and] we have limited evidence of police action in response to citizen reports.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a citizen’s perspective, then, not much changed. It’s little wonder that no meaningful change in police behavior led to no meaningful change in outcomes. Ultimately, this is less a story about community policing and more about the general difficulty of organizational change.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">The lead research article of the most recent issue of Science is “Community policing does not build citizen trust in police or reduce crime in the Global South”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello world!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/meta/2021/12/01/hello-world.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello world!" /><published>2021-12-01T10:38:39-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-01T10:38:39-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/meta/2021/12/01/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/meta/2021/12/01/hello-world.html">&lt;p&gt;Hi. Welcome to Disorganized Behavior, a blog about social, behavioral, and information science. Among other things, I will discuss recent scientific research and share techniques for data analytics. I hope you find something interesting to read!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="meta" /><summary type="html">Hi. Welcome to Disorganized Behavior, a blog about social, behavioral, and information science. Among other things, I will discuss recent scientific research and share techniques for data analytics. I hope you find something interesting to read!</summary></entry></feed>