<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://dsethlewis.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://dsethlewis.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-02T10:58:28-05:00</updated><id>https://dsethlewis.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Disorganized Behavior</title><subtitle>A blog about social, behavioral, and information sciences</subtitle><entry><title type="html">An absence of evidence of community policing</title><link href="https://dsethlewis.github.io/2021/12/01/absence-of-evidence.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An absence of evidence of community policing" /><published>2021-12-01T13:44:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-01T13:44:00-05:00</updated><id>https://dsethlewis.github.io/2021/12/01/absence-of-evidence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dsethlewis.github.io/2021/12/01/absence-of-evidence.html">&lt;p&gt;The lead research article of the most recent issue of &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.abd3446&quot;&gt;“Community policing does not build citizen trust in police or reduce crime in the Global South”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research was a collaboration of 27 researchers in five countries to run a large-scale field experiment across South America, Africa, and Asia. When these studies are published, it’s a big deal, if for no other reason than the difficulty and cost of executing a study of this scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because high-quality empirical research is necessarily so scarce, these large-scale field experiments carry a lot of weight with policy wonks, and, one hopes, policymakers. When arguing for or against a community policing program, someone, somewhere, is going to cite this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On its face, that’s not really a problem. But they’re going to cite the article without actually reading it. It’s almost inevitable. Scientific articles are long, dense, highly technical, and, frankly, a bit repetitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why it’s so important to get the headline right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And why I’m frustrated that this one is misleading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not wrong, &lt;em&gt;per se&lt;/em&gt;. But “Community policing does not build citizen trust in police or reduce crime in the Global South” implies a certain pair of relationships that the study doesn’t even really analyze:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enacting community policing behaviors does not lead to higher levels of citizen trust in police.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enacting community policing behaviors does not reduce crime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these propositions, I have made explicit what the title implies the independent variable in the study is. But community policing itself is not the actual independent variable in the study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, the study looked at police reforms &lt;em&gt;intended&lt;/em&gt; to lead to community policing and found that they did not succeed in doing so: “The police implemented the interventions unevenly and incompletely…[and] we have limited evidence of police action in response to citizen reports.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a citizen’s perspective, then, not much changed. It’s little wonder that no meaningful change in police behavior led to no meaningful change in outcomes. Ultimately, this is less a story about community policing and more about the general difficulty of organizational change.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The lead research article of the most recent issue of Science is “Community policing does not build citizen trust in police or reduce crime in the Global South”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello world!</title><link href="https://dsethlewis.github.io/meta/2021/12/01/hello-world.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello world!" /><published>2021-12-01T10:38:39-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-01T10:38:39-05:00</updated><id>https://dsethlewis.github.io/meta/2021/12/01/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dsethlewis.github.io/meta/2021/12/01/hello-world.html">&lt;p&gt;Hi. Welcome to Disorganized Behavior, a blog about social, behavioral, and information science. Among other things, I will discuss recent scientific research and share techniques for data analytics. I hope you find something interesting to read!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="meta" /><summary type="html">Hi. Welcome to Disorganized Behavior, a blog about social, behavioral, and information science. Among other things, I will discuss recent scientific research and share techniques for data analytics. I hope you find something interesting to read!</summary></entry></feed>